## Jeremy R McIntyre

Senior Cloud Infrastructure Engineer Cincinnati, OH

#### **SUMMARY**

Cell: 513-846-0934

**Secondary:** 513-239-7104

Email:jmcintyre@outlook.com

Experienced Cloud Infrastructure Engineer with a demonstrated work history across multiple industries. Skilled in Docker, Kubernetes, Linux/Unix, CI/CD, AWS, Infra as Code (IaC), Networking, and scripting. Strong cloud professional with an Associate's degree focused in Network Engineering from Sinclair Community College.

#### **SOFTWARE/SKILLS**

AWS Managed Service Offering, Docker, Kubernetes, Helm/Helmfile, ArgoCD, Python, Bash, IaC: Cloudformation, Terraform

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

### Finite State, Columbus, Ohio (Remote)

Infrastructure Engineer (AWS) 7/19/2021 - Present

- Built and supported CI/CD solutions for new and existing apps
- Modified multi-tenant SaaS app codebase to enable single-tenant instance deployment and deployed for customers
- Application and infrastructure deployments using AWS terraform/cloudformation, codepipeline, and Github actions
- Trained incoming infrastructure/platform engineers
- Participated in regular code reviews for peers
- Migrated critical global search infrastructure code to Terraform from Cloudformation
- Worked closely with developers to architect infrastructure solutions for new applications
- Migration of ECS services to EKS utilizing helm/helmfile, and ArgoCD
- Enabled local app, infrastructure, and platform development via kubernetes in docker (KIND)
- Worked to develop and maintain multiple on-prem solutions including air gapped using Replicated

#### Apex Supply Chain Technologies, Mason, Ohio

### <u>DevOps Engineer 3/1/2018 – 7/9/2021</u>

- Support and deploy patches to containerized java web applications hosted in AWS and Azure
- AWS EKS/kubernetes administration, managed access into environments for applications and users
- Maintain and support Docker and K8s environments
- Administer Apex's self-hosted docker image repository running on EC2
- Utilize and administer AWS SNS, AMQ, S3, and EC2 among others
- Create and maintain deployment scripts and CI/CD pipelines in Jenkins
- Create and maintain git repos for tooling, scripts, and documentation
- Work closely with dev and db teams for application requirements, code changes, and db changes
- Instrument applications with internal and external monitoring to measure performance and uptime
- Troubleshoot and document application performance and outages in on-call rotation
- Provided support for the production environment managing environment health, ticket triage, and participated in an on-call rotation to engage in after-hours critical incidents

## <u>Computer Systems Engineer 4/27/2015 - 3/1/2018</u>

- Triaged support ticket queue
- Collaborated with infrastructure, security, and network teams on projects
- Monitored antivirus and security reports
- POC for security incidents
- Scripted installation and removal of commonly used software
- Managed active directory; domain account administration
- Managed Office 365 accounts
- Trained new interns and Co-Ops
- Configure and deployed endpoints including laptops, desktops, cell phones, and desk phones
- Windows and Linux server host monitoring and security patching

### SpliceNet, West Chester, Ohio

## Infrastructure Support Specialist 8/1/2014 – 4/24/2015

- Contracted to Bilstein for staff augmentation and training of new Co-Ops
- Supported and maintained Windows Server and endpoints for over 20 customers remotely and onsite as needed
- Implemented and maintained data backup and recovery solutions for a majority of customers
- Worked with vendors to support specialized productivity applications in production and law firm environments
- Deployment, administration of Office365
- Deployment and administration of endpoint management tools
- Available for on-call and remote support

# Bilstein of America, Hamilton, Ohio

## <u>IT Support Technician 5/01/2012 - 7/31/2014</u>

- Maintained helpdesk ticket queue
- Automated PC deployment
- Deployed and managed antivirus software
- Supported end users in a production environment
- Scripted installs and patches of software across the network
- Helped to automated many departmental processes
- Documented processes and procedures
- Answered helpdesk calls and IT tickets regarding technical issues
- Audited IT department for 5S compliance
- Audited workstations for software compliance on a monthly basis
- Remotely monitored PCs and servers
- Managed active directory; domain account administration, exchange administration
- Supported and deployed CAD software including Catia, SolidEdge, and AutoCAD
- Responsible for purchasing, deploying, and maintaining Verizon and AT&T mobile phones
- Trained new IT Co-Ops

#### **EDUCATION**

## **Sinclair Community College**

Dayton, Ohio

- Associate degree in Computer Information Systems, Network Engineering
- Cumulative GPA: 3.5 / Major GPA: 4.0